# **Othman Shareef**

**\** (+964) 7507313459

**(**+90) 5369930799

**Gender:** Male

**Email address:** <u>othmanosx@gmail.com</u>

Website: othman.itechnopro.com

in LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/othmanosx

## **ABOUT ME**

I'm a web developer with a demonstrated history of working in the Information Technology & Services industry for more than 6 years. I love working on projects, converting ideas and UI's to functional web applications and enjoy doing the front-end part because of my skills in user interface design. I create websites and web apps using javascript frameworks. I have skills in Software Engineering, Front-end web development, React JS, UI Design, Graphic Design, Photography, Translation, Blogging, Software Reviewing, and Management. I'm fast learner with, strong media and communication professional with an engineering degree focused in mechanical engineering from University of Mosul.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Web developer

**ITECH** [ 12/2014 - Current ]

- www.itechnopro.com

City: Remote

Email address: info@itechnopro.com

- Website owner, manager and organizer.
- Front-end web developer.
- Professional blogger, copywriter, software reviewer, articles and report writer with 6+ years of experience.
- Sponsored and collaborated with many big software companies including Tenorshare, iMobie, GearBest, Digiarty, and many others.
- Graphics designer with 5+ years of experience.
- Marketing & Social Media Specialist.
- Website management and content publishing with excellent skills.
- Search Engine Optimization Specialist.
- Offer technical support to company clients and troubleshoot technical problems.

# **Software Engineer**

**Tenoreshare inc.** [ 2016 - 2021 ]

- https://www.tenorshare.com/

City: Remote

- $\circ$  English Arabic translator, converted the company's website and software user interface language from English to Arabic.
- Graphic Designer (Photoshop).
- Data management using Excel (Microsoft Office suite).
- Sponsored and collaborated with the company and did software reviews and tested new products and software.

## **Mechanical engineer**

Municipality of Erbil Governorate [ 07/2018 – 08/2018 ]

City: Erbil Country: Iraq

- Work on assessing and monitoring project requirements
- Measuring performance of mechanical devices and engines
- Maintaining equipment to ensure it's safe, reliable and efficient
- Using computer-aided design and modeling software
- Producing and implementing designs and check procedures
- Testing, evaluating, modifying and re-testing products
- Writing reports and documentation
- Providing technical advice

## **PROJECTS**

## Weather web app (React JS)

[ 06/02/2021 - 13/02/2021 ]

- Provide detailed weather forecasts over a 6 day period updated each day for more than 2000 cities in the world.
- Charts provide wind speed, temperature, humidity and visibility.

Used libraries and dependencies:

- react v17.0.1
- ∘ chart.js v2.9.4
- chartjs-plugin-colorschemes v0.4.0
- fontawesome v5.0.7
- bootstrap v4.0.0
- ∘ jquery v3.2.1
- ∘ ajax v1.12.9

Live Demo: <a href="https://weather-app-othman.netlify.app">https://weather-app-othman.netlify.app</a>

Code Repo: <a href="https://github.com/Othmanosx/weather\_app\_js">https://github.com/Othmanosx/weather\_app\_js</a>

## **Mood Analyzer (Angular)**

[ 28/01/2021 - Current ]

A web app that analyzes human faces and detects changes with emotions depending on the facial expression of image.

## **Technologies**

- 1. Angular
- 2. Flask
- 3. Firebase (for deployment)

Code Repo: https://github.com/Othmanosx/MoodApp

### Hangman Game (ReactJS)

[28/01/2021 - 05/02/2021]

Hangman is a word guessing game which I developed using ReactJS Javascript framework in which the user guesses the word generated randomly by the game from an API.

Live Demo: <a href="https://hangman-sand-team.netlify.app/">https://hangman-sand-team.netlify.app/</a>

Code Repo: <a href="https://github.com/Othmanosx/hangman\_react\_js">https://github.com/Othmanosx/hangman\_react\_js</a>

## FindYours (in development)

[ 02/2021 - Current ]

The idea of the project is to help people find their missing stuff, will let people post the things they lost and let people post the things they found, every post will contain the info a user may need to contact the person. Every province will have its own section.

- 1. Technologies and dependencies
- 2. React is
- 3. Material UI CSS Framework
- 4. Firebase
- 5. Redux
- 6. Jest testing
- 7. Prettier
- 8. Eslint

Repo: https://github.com/murtaja1/find\_yours

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# **Bachelor in Mechanical Engineering**

**Mosul University** 

Address: Mosul (Iraq)

## Front-End Web Development (ReactJS)

**Re:Coded** [ 13/01/2021 - Current ]

Address: Erbil (Iraq)

https://www.re-coded.com/

## Full Stack Web Development (Python&Angular)

Kodluyoruz

Address: Ankara (Turkey) https://www.kodluyoruz.org/

# COVID-19: Operational Planning Guidelines and COVID-19 Partners Platform to support country preparedness and response

World Health Organization

https://www.who.int/

# Management and Facilitation of an After Action Review (AAR)

**World Health Organization** 

https://www.who.int/

# Power Skills: Business Communication, Agile Methodologies, Team Work, Time Management

**Re:Coded** [ 01/2021 - 04/2021 ]

www.re-coded.com

## **Retail sales skills**

mselect

https://www.mselect.ig/

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s):

**Arabic** 

Other language(s):

**English** Turkish

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

## **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## Web Development

Material Ui / Netlify / Redux / CSS Frameworks / CI / CD / DevOps/CICD: Travis CI, Heroku, Netlify, Firebase, Webpack, Jenkins, Terraform / Git workflow / State Management / Sprint Planning / Context API / Scrum / Ag ile Methodology / GIT (GitHub) / VScode / Reactjs / ReactJS / Web Development: HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript

## Design

AutoCAD / SolidWorks / UI Design (Figma) / Adobe Illustratior / Photoshop

#### Other

Microsoft Powerpoint / Organizational and planning skills / Microsoft Office / Microsoft Word / Social Media / Microsoft Excel